答案
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
史蒂文！
Steven!
石榴！
Garnet!
现在已经是早上了吗？
Is it morning already?
现在是午夜，生日快乐，史蒂文！
It's midnight. Happy Birthday, Steven.
哦，天哪，你总算要告诉我
Oh, man, are you finally gonna tell me
你是红宝石和蓝宝石的融合体
that you're a fusion of the gems Ruby and Sapphire
来兑现你的承诺了？
like you promised?
你早就知道这个了，史蒂文
You already know about all that, Steven.
当然啦
It's true.
但你不知道的是红宝石和蓝宝石是如何相遇的
But what you don't know is how Ruby and Sapphire first met.
我-滴-神！我不知道！
O-m-g! I don't!
地球，5750年前
The earth, 5,750 years ago.
这里是个前途光明的宝石殖民地
It was a promising site of a new gem colony,
但进展被一小股顽固的
but progress was being thwarted
反叛势力所阻挠
by a small persistent group of rebels.
一队外交宝石人
A team of diplomatic gems
被从母世界派来调查此事
were sent from homeworld to investigate.
云霄竞技场的造型与《星球大战5：帝国反攻》中的云霄都市类似
在那些宝石人中有蓝宝石
Among those gems was Sapphire,
一个非常稀有的母世界贵族
a rare aristocratic homeworld gem
拥有能预见未来的能力
with the power to see into the future.
分配给她的有三个红宝石...
Assigned to her were three rubies...
哈！哈！哈！
Hup! Hup! Hup!
...寻常的士兵，任务是保护她
...common soldiers with a mission to protect her.
嘿，等不及看到那些反贼来这里了
Hey, can't wait for those rebels to get here.
没错
Yeah.
当我看到那些逆子时，
When I see those rebels,
我要一拳直接打在脸中央
I'm gonna punch them right in their faces.
你说的什么？
What are you saying?
我要将她们的全身打个遍，
I'm gonna punch them all over their bodies,
然后这就结束了
and then it'll be over.
如果我打你呢？
What if I just punch you?
哦，何苦
Oh, come on.
当我们融合后我们就能一起打他们了
We'll punch them together when we fuse.
那正是为什么他们派了，呃，我们三个
That's why they sent, uh, three of us.
三个这！
Three this!
哦，我，呃，我很抱歉，我-
Oh, I, um, I'm so sorry, I --
让我，呃-
let me, uh --
我很好
I'm fine.
哈？
What?
这没什么，这是注定会发生的
It's okay. It was bound to happen.
我-哦
I -- oh.
好的
Okay.
现在，请等在这里，我必须要履行我的职责了
Now, please wait here. I must attend to my duties.
好的-呃-没错
Right-Uh-Yes.
蓝宝石被蓝钻石召唤到地球
Sapphire had been called to earth by blue diamond
是专门为了分享她所预见的未来
specifically to share her vision of the future.
我的钻石，我到达了
My diamond, I've arrived.
蓝钻石开口了
Blue diamond spoke.
“蓝宝石，告诉我这里会发生什么”
"Sapphire, tell me what will happen here."
蓝钻石向蓝宝石寻求战斗的结局与古希腊社会中先知的作用类似
不论是历史上还是神话中重要人物都有在参与战斗前咨询先知委员会的习惯
我预见到反叛军攻击了云霄竞技场
I foresee the rebels attacking the cloud arena.
在她们被包围前，她们会摧毁
Before they are cornered, they will destroy
七个宝石人的实体，
the physical forms of seven gems,
包括我的两个红宝石护卫和我自己
including two of my Ruby guards and myself.
一旦我的我的实体被摧毁，
Immediately after my form is destroyed,
反叛军就会被抓获
the rebels will be captured.
叛乱到此为止
The rebellion ends here.
“谢谢，蓝宝石”蓝钻石长舒了一口气
"Thank you, Sapphire," blue diamond said, relieved.
“那是我需要知道的全部”
"That's all I needed to know."
我盼望我在母世界重组后
I look forward to speaking with you again
再次与您交谈
once I reform back on homeworld.
蓝宝石知道她会成为牺牲品
Sapphire knew she would be a casualty,
但这并没有让她担心
but it did not faze her.
她看到过呈现在面前的一生
She saw her whole life laid out before her,
而她早已接受了那一切
and she had already accepted all of it.
如此漂亮的用来建立殖民地的星球啊！
What a beautiful place to build a colony.
我希望我能多看这个星球两眼
I wish I could have seen more of this planet.
呃，还有时间啊
Uh, there's still time.
那真是个不错的想法
That is a nice thought.
但，没时间了
But, no.
蓝钻石，离开这个星球！
Blue diamond, leave this planet.
这个殖民地不会被完成的！
This colony will not be completed.
是叛军！
It's the rebels!
你是谁？快现身！
Who are you? Show yourselves!
我们是水晶战士！
We are The Crystal Gems.
攻击准时发生了
The attack was right on schedule.
谢谢你，红宝石，你尽力了
Thank you, Ruby. You did your best.
红宝石突然间明白了蓝宝石的意思
Ruby suddenly realized what Sapphire meant.
她早知道红宝石会失败
She had known that Ruby would fail.
蓝宝石已经接受了
Sapphire had accepted it,
但红宝石-红宝石拒绝！
but Ruby -- Ruby could not.
不！
No!
什么？
What?
石榴此处的装束与《睡美人》中爱洛公主在“Pink and Blue”场景中的着装类似
哈？
What?
这-这是什么情况？
What -- what is this?
等等，这是-
Wait. This is --
嗯？
hm?
我们走
Let's go.
呃，拜拜？
Uh, bye.
这是-
Is this --
愤怒的人群围住了红宝石和蓝宝石
The furious crowd closed in around Ruby and Sapphire.
她们从没见过两个不同类型的宝石相融合
They had never seen fusion of two different types of gems.
“难以置信”
"Unbelievable."
"令人作呕"
"Disgusting."
“闻所未闻”
"This is unheard of."
蓝钻石的声音穿过了人群
Blue diamond's voice cut through the crowd.
“反叛军逃走了”
"The rebels have fled.
蓝宝石，你描述的情景可不是这样的“
Sapphire, this is not the scenario you described."
这不是我预见的，我不知道发生了什么，我-
This is not what I saw. I don't know what happened.I-
不，都怪我
No, it was me.
“显然，”蓝钻石说道
"Clearly," said blue diamond.
“你怎敢与我的部族的一员融合”
"How dare you fuse with a member of my court."
此处体现的等级观念与现实社会曾经对不同种族的人婚姻的抵制相似——最明显的例子是印度
原谅我吧，我-
Forgive me. I --
“你会付出破碎的代价！”
"you will be broken for this."
等等！
Wait!
你在做什么？！
What are you doing?!
不！
Noooo!
为什么你要这么做？
Why'd you do that?
我必须带你回到上面
I have to get you back up there.
她们要打碎你
They were gonna break you.
谁在乎？那里有无数个我
Who cares? There's tons of me.
我们现在该怎么办？
What do we do now?
蓝宝石知道她生命中的每一刻-
Sapphire had known every moment of her life --
事件与时间
how it would happen and when.
但因为红宝石冲动的行为，
But because of Ruby's impulsive gesture,
她突然间跳出了命运的轨迹
she suddenly jumped the track of fate.
而从那一瞬间起的一切
And everything from that instant on
既反常又新奇
was wrong and new.
她看不清未来，她无法移动，
She couldn't see. She couldn't move.
她-冻住了
She was -- frozen.
啊！
Ah!
我们得带你离开这里
We have to get you out of here.
来吧
Come on.
好吧，这暂时来讲足够了
All right, this should be good for now.
谢谢你
Thank you.
蛤？
Wha?
我应该是什么样的红宝石？
What kind of Ruby am I supposed to be?
看看这个僵局
Look at this.
都是我的错，害你被困在这里
It's all my fault you're stranded here.
我该怎么拯救你？
How am I gonna save you?
你已经做到了
You already did.
什么？
What?
你已经救过我了
You already saved me.
我看到过别的宝石人融合，
I've seen gems fuse before,
但我自己对此毫无体会
but I had no idea that's what it felt like.
我一直以为-
I always thought --
我从没意识到融合-
I never realized that fusion --
-自我就这么消失了
that you disappear like that.
之前从不是这样
It's never like that.
无论什么时候我参与融合，我都在那里
Whenever I fuse, it's always just been me,
只是更强大了
but bigger.
我从没体会过第三只眼
I've never had a third eye before.
我还从没有过第二只呢
I've never had more than one.
那真不错
It was nice.
是啊
Yeah.
去了何方？
♪ where did we go?
做了何事？
♪ What did we do?
我认为我们创造了全新事物
♪ I think we made something entirely new ♪
而那不只是我
♪ and it wasn't quite me
而也不只是你
♪ and it wasn't quite you
我认为那是个全新的事物
♪ I think it was someone entirely new ♪
哦
♪ oh
呃
♪ um
而我不禁去回想
♪ well, I just can't stop thinkin' ♪
那么
♪ so
呃
♪ um
你说我与众不同？
♪ did you say I was different? ♪
你从前未体验过？
♪ And you hadn't before?
当然不
♪ Of course not
怎么可能有过？
♪ when would I have ever?
我很抱歉
♪ I'm so sorry
不不，不用
♪ no, no, don't be
你永远被困在这里
♪ and now you're here forever ♪
你又如何？
♪ what about you?
我该如何？
♪ What about me?
既然你在
♪ Well, you're here, too
我们就在一起
♪ we're here together
此处舞蹈场景类似《睡美人》中爱洛公主与菲利普王子“Once upon a dream”的场景
我又回来了
I was back.
我是某个人，而我不知道是谁
I was someone, and I didn't know who.
但，我感觉我能理解我奇异，全新的形态了
But, i felt like i was getting the hang of my strange, new form.
然后就摔了一跤
And then I fell.
啊！
Ah!
嗷
Ow.
啊！
Ah!
不要伤害她！
Don't hurt her!
不要伤害...我？
Don't hurt...Me?
是你-那个融合体
It's you -- the fusion.
我们不是故意融合的
We didn't mean to fuse.
不过，这次是
Well, we did this time.
我们会解除融合的
We'll unfuse.
我们会-我们会-
We'll -- we'll --
不，不，不用，我很高兴再次见到你
no, no, please. I'm glad to see you again.
正是她们-
And there they were --
玫瑰·石英，反叛军的首领，
Rose Quartz, the leader of the rebellion
与她那恐怖的，叛逆的珍珠
and her terrifying renegade, Pearl.
我不让你，不舒服吗？
I don't upset you?
谁在乎我的感受？
Who cares about how i feel?
你的感受才是真正有意思的
How you feel is bound to be much more interesting.
我的感受？
How I feel?
我-我感到迷茫...
I-I feel lost...
还有恐惧...
And scared...
还有-还有快乐
And -- and happy.
为什么我这么确定，我愿意如此
Why am I so sure,that I'd rather be this
而不是我本应成为的样子？
than everything I was supposed to be?
而且为什么我愿意做这个
And that I'd rather do this
而不是我本应做的事情？
than everything I was supposed to do?
欢迎来到地球
Welcome to earth.
能-能告诉我吗？为什么红宝石能够改变命运？
C-Can you tell me, how was Ruby able to alter fate?
为-为什么蓝宝石愿意放弃一切？
W-Why was Sapphire willing to give up everything?
我是什-什么？
W-What am I?
不要再问问题了
No more questions.
永远不要质疑这一切
Don't ever question this.
你已经是答案了
You already are the answer.
那么，是什么？
So, what was it?
那个答案？
The answer?
爱
Love.
喔！
Wow.
我就知道！
I knew it.
我也是
So did I.
本集石榴的回忆部分画风致敬洛特·雷妮格的剪影动画风格
本集同时也是对同性恋者接受自我，出柜，然后开始第一段正式的同性关系的隐喻。
母世界对红宝石与蓝宝石的融合的观念与当今社会对同性恋者的观念类似。
同时主创团队确认蓝宝石与红宝石的关系属于同性关系。